Vincent Ulap C. Camilon



Northview 1, Batasan Hills, Quezon City 1126





(+639) 156 581 856

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 6 years in full-stack web and mobile development. Proficient in Spring Framework, React, React Native, and DevOps deployment. Currently a senior lead ensuring quality execution and collaboration. Experienced in the financial sector using Waterfall, Agile Scrum, and Kanban methodologies. Collaborated with teams from the United Kingdom, India, Myanmar, Bangladesh, and the Philippines.

EMPLOYMENT

Lead & Senior Lead Software Engineer at MDI Novare

Nov 2021 - Present

- O Development and stakeholder management for client (Metrobank).
- O Modernized a legacy system for processes such as check encashment and cash deposit for digital banking. Led the creation of a dynamic form app.
- O Developed a financial literacy and investment mobile app for new investors of Metrobank with over 100K+ downloads and 4.0+ star rating.
- People manager and instructor for MDI Novare's boot camp programs.

Associate & Software Engineer at Finastra

April 2019 - Nov 2021

- O Developed new features and improved components for online banking. Customized banking products and supported global services for clients in Myanmar and Bangladesh. Served a collective online customer base exceeding an estimated 1 million users.
- Frequently served as Scrum Master and handled DevOps activities, including server maintenance, automation, and product releases.

Junior Developer Volunteer & Intern at BotBros AI

May 2018 - Feb 2019

- O Built an English Learning and a Human Resource system for local clients.
- O Created a mobile-responsive informational site for a client in Germany.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Core Values Champion Award (Grit) - Pinnacle Awards

MDI Novare - 2023

Recognized for excellence and performance. The annual event honors individuals and teams for innovative tech approaches and outstanding contributions. Won against 261 core value nominations, highlighting exceptional work among the best in the organization.

Microsoft Certified: **Azure Fundamentals**

Jun 2021

Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Fundamentals

Sep 2021

EDUCATION

De La Salle University - Manila

Bachelor of Science Degree in Information Technology

O Consistent Dean's First Honors List Awardee AY 2017 - 2018

SKILLS

Frameworks & Languages

 Spring Framework Java

React React Native

AngularJS

TypeScript

Technologies & Database

O Git o npm/yarn

Jira Azure DevOps

Apache Tomcat MySQL

PostgreSQL O DB2

Managerial

• Team Leadership • Performance Evaluation

O Admin Monitoring O Career Coaching

PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS

Web

 UX40 Core Transactions - Metrobank Oct 2022 - Mar 2023 Full-stack system for bank core transactions of teller and client-facing users. Implemented using Next.js, Spring Framework, and Turborepo.

O Digital Channels - Finastra Apr 2019 - Nov 2021 Real time online banking solution. Developed both off-the-shelf and customized versions. Built using AngularJS, and Spring Framework.

Mobile

O Earnest - Metrobank

Mar 2023 - Present

Mobile app that aims to make investing easy. Financial education app that has banking integration for investment. Implemented using React Native.